

Web Developer

ismailcourr@gmail.com | github.com/ismailco | linkedin.com/in/ismailcourr | ismailcourr.tech

SUMMARY

Software Developer with experience building responsive Web Apps using React, Redux, Ruby on Rails, and Tailwindcss. Skilled in code reviewing and optimizing processes. Completed a Remote Full-Stack Web Development Program and possesses technical skills in website performance, accessibility, and web security.

EXPERIENCE

Co.Lab.io

Front-end Developer

December 2022 - February 2023, Remote

- Collaborated with cross-functional team members, including product managers, designers, and back-end developers, to develop and deliver a post-surgery recovery and follow-up PWA app using React, Redux, and Tailwindess
- Successfully integrated APIs using Axios to fetch and send data to the backend, resulting in an optimized application with an average page load time of 1.8 seconds
- Utilized performance metrics such as Google's Lighthouse score to ensure a responsive and user-friendly interface, achieving a score of 90+ for accessibility, best practices, and SEO
- Identified and resolved technical issues during the development and testing phases, resulting in a stable application with a 99.99% uptime and no reported bugs.

MICROVERSE

Technical Support Engineer (Code Reviewer)

April 2022 - Present, Remote

- Provided quality checks by giving detailed code reviews on more than 900 technical projects within a cross-functional team in order to optimize the code review process in an all-remote, global startup
- Assessed code clarity, style, and best practices on project PRs
- Tested API integrations for 200+ React capstone projects

HIGHLIGHTED

January 2020 - April 2022, Remote

MaRock

- Inspired by the Boulevard urban music festival in Morocco, MaRock is a music festival website
- Take 2 days to complete based on the "CC-Global-Summit-2015" in behance.net
- Built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flexbox, Grid, and Responsive Development

Film Guru

- Created using React.is, Film Guru is a web app that returns information about movies
- Gives the user the option to like or add a comment to a movie
- Uses the OMDb API to get data about movies and series

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

January 2022 – January 2023

Remote Full-Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, Javascript, ReactJS, Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, Webpack, Vite, Vitest, Jest, Unite test, Web app performance, SEO, English, Strong computer science fundamentals, Figma to Code, Agile, Teamwork, Communication

CERTIFICATES

Google IT Support Certificate

January 2022

CS50's AP® Computer Science Principles

January 2022

Co.Lab Software Development Certificate

February 2023

FreeCode Camp Responsive Web Design

December 2020